Guide to the Dorothy M. Horstmann Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- General Files, 1927-1995, Series I
  - Yale-in-China
    - General, 1973-1974, undated (Box 12, Folder 268)
    - "Report from the Yale Group Visiting China", 1974 (Box 12, Folder 269 - 271)
    - Trip notes, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 272)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital. Committee on Infection Control, 1982-1984, undated (Box 12, Folder 273)
  - Yale-New Haven Teachers Institute, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 274)
  - Yale University
    - General, 1971-1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 275)
    - Ezra Stiles Fellow, 1970-1990 (Box 12, Folder 276)
    - Health Services OB/GYN Review Committee, 1973-1976, undated (Box 12, Folder 277 - 279)
    - School of Medicine
      - General, 1976-1994 (Box 13, Folder 280)
      - Alumni reunion, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 281)
      - Appointments and Promotions Committee, 1973-1976, undated (Box 13, Folder 282)
      - Associates of the Yale Medical Library, 1976-1990 (Box 13, Folder 283)
      - Beaumont Club and Nathan Smith Club, 1972-1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 284)
      - Curriculum Committee, 1946, 1960-1961, undated (Box 13, Folder 285)
      - Department of Epidemiology and Public Health
        - General, 1960-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 286)
        - Annual reports, 1969-1994 (Box 13, Folder 287)
        - Policy Committee, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 288)
      - Department of Pediatrics
        - General, 1963-1975, undated (Box 13, Folder 289)
        - Annual reports, 1967-1994 (Box 13, Folder 290 - 291)
        - Bacteriology Laboratories, 1972-1978 (Box 13, Folder 292)
        - Joseph E. Smadel Lecture, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 293)
      - Office of the Dean
        - General, 1964-1968 (Box 13, Folder 294)
        - Review of Robert Berliner's deanship [restricted until January 1, 2054; see Box 13a], 1977-1978, undated (Box 13, Folder 295)
      - Poliomyelitis Study Group, 1948-1949, undated (Box 13, Folder 296)
      - Preventive Medicine and Public Health, 1946-1956, 1962, undated (Box 13, Folder 297)
      - Section of History of Medicine, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 298)
      - Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, 1958-1986 (Box 13, Folder 299)
      - Office of the Dean. Review of Robert Berliner's deanship (Box 13a)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Materials in box 54 are restricted until January 1, 2054 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Women's issues
      - General, 1970-1976, undated (Box 14, Folder 300 - 302)
      - Advisory Committee on the Education of Women, 1974-1976, undated (Box 14, Folder 303)
      - Committee on the Status of Professional Women at Yale [Greene Committee], 1970-1971, undated (Box 14, Folder 304 - 305)
  - Yale University Press, 1976-1984 (Box 14, Folder 306)
  - Z, 1974-1993 (Box 14, Folder 307)
  - Correspondence regarding lectures, 1962-1987 (Box 14, Folder 308 - 309)
  - Unidentified, 1948-1981, undated (Box 14, Folder 310)
- Writings, 1946 -1994, n.d., Series II
  Arranged chronologically, the series includes Horstmann's unpublished lectures and correspondence concerning publications. Though Horstmann contributed well over 150 professional papers, these, being published, are not in the files.
  The lecture files rarely contain word for word typescripts of her talks. Rather, one finds in them hand written outlines on paper or index cards in Horstmann's large round penmanship. Some lecture notes served for more than one appearance, as can occasionally be noticed from the numbering of the pages. Because Horstmann gave so many talks on rubella and poliomyelitis, those topics appear often.
  A comprehensive bibliography of Horstmann's published work is in Series VI.
  - "Epidemiology of Poliomyelitis" [Monmouth County Medical Society], 1946 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "Some Clinical Problems in Acute Poliomyelitis" [Rocky Mountain Conference on Poliomyelitis, includes discussions], 1946 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "The Incubation Period in Human Poliomyelitis" with J. R. Paul, [Interurban Clinical Club], 1947 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "The Incubation Period in Human Poliomyelitis" [Conference on the Epidemiology of Poliomyelitis, New Haven], 1947 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Epidemiology of Poliomyelitis [Polio League], 1952 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "Poliomyelitis- Modern Views" [Symposium on Acute Infectious Diseases], 1952 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - "Poliomyelitis Virus in the Blood of Orally Infected Monkeys and Chimpanzees" [Federation], 1952 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - "Recent Advances in Our Knowledge of the Virus of Poliomyelitis (Storrs, Connecticut, Memphis), [1952] (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Recent Developments in Poliomyelitis Research [Brooklyn Academy of Pediatrics], 1952 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - "March of Dimes Campaign Furthers Poliomyelitis Research" [Yale Interprets the News, radio program], 1953 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - "Viremia in Human Poliomyelitis" [Interurban Clinical Club], 1953 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - "Epidemiology Aspects of Poliomyelitis" [American College of Physicians], 1954 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Immunization Against Poliomyelitis (California), 1954 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Poliomyelitis [Sixth International Congress for Microbiology], 1954 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - "Problems in the Prevention of Poliomyelitis" [Symposium on Infectious Diseases, Saskatchewan], 1954 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - "Progress in Immunization Against Poliomyelitis [Symposium on Infectious Diseases, Saskatchewan], 1954 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Viremia in Human Poliomyelitis [Board of Directors, Yale-New Haven Hospital, Hartford], 1954 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - "Poliomyelitis, 1955" [Medical Society of Delaware] (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Poliomyelitis Immunization with Vaccines [Medical Society of Delaware], 1955 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - "Poliomyelitis, 1956" [Society of American Bacteriologists, New York], 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - "Applications of Epidemiology to Clinical Medicine" (Madison), 1956 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - "The Ecology of Poliomyelitis" [Conference on Poliomyelitis, San Francisco], 1956 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Pathogenesis of Poliomyelitis, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Poliomyelitis; Immunity Status of Different Population Groups and Indications for Vaccination [Exhibit, Pediatric Congress, Copenhagen], 1956 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Visit of Four Russian Scientists, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - "Poliomyelitis: Recent Advances in Diagnosis" [Alumni Symposium], 1956 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Type III Vaccine [Yale Medical Society], [1956] (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Yale Poliomyelitis Study Unit [Yale Alumni Reunion; Hamden Probus Club], 1956 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Discussion of David Bodian's "Mechanism of Infection with Polioviruses" [New York Academy of Sciences], 1957 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Vaccination Against Poliomyelitis [Discussion, Fourth International Poliomyelitis Congress, Philadelphia], 1957 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - "Poliomyelitis in the Near East" [Symposium on Diseases of the Near East], 1957 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - "Enteric (Echo) Virus Infections and Clinical Disease" [American College of Physicians; Storrs], 1958 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - "The Epidemiology of Poliomyelitis [U. S. Navy, Bethesda], 1958 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - "Factors in the Use and Spread of Attenuated Poliovirus Vaccine" [with J. R. Paul and J. C. Niederman,, American Epidemiological Society], 1958 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Rubella, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Vaccination Against Poliomyelitis [Discussion, Fourth International Poliomyelitis Congress, Philadelphia], 1958 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - "An Attenuated Poliovirus Vaccine Trial in a Village Community" [American Pediatric Society], 1959 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - "Community Susceptibility Studies" in Perspectives in Pediatric Virology, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Poliomyelitis (Cincinnati), 1959 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - "Reporting on a Visit to the U.S.S.R., Poland and Czechoslovakia to Review Work on Live Poliovirus Vaccine", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 40 - 43)
  - "Report on Live Poliovirus Vaccination in the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, Poland and Czechoslovakia, August-October", 1959, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - "Thermal Sensitivity of Poliovirus Strains Isolated During an Oral Vaccine Field Trial", with Isao Yoshioka and J.T. Riordan, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - "Viremia in Echo 9 Virus Infection" [American Association of Immunologists], 1959 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - "Current Status of Live Poliovirus Vaccines [Connecticut Public Health Association], 1960 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - "The Advantages of Oral Poliovirus Vaccine in Immunizing Young Children" (Montevideo), 1961 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - "Could It Be a Virus Infection?" (Boston), 1961 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Live Attenuated Viruses (Chicago), 1961 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Middletown Project on Sabin Oral Vaccine (Washington, Atlanta), 1961, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Oral Poliovirus Vaccine [St. Raphael's Hospital, Philadelphia, Chicago], 1961 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - "Poliomyelitis, 1961" (Madison) (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Poliomyelitis [Sesquicentennial], 1961 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Immunization of Pre-school Children with Oral Poliovirus Vaccine with J. R. Paul, M. Godenne-McReo, R. H. Green, E. M. Opton, J.C. Niederman, E. P. Isacson, and R. H. Green, 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - "Enteroviruses" (Syracuse), 1962 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - "The Epidemiology of Poliomyelitis and Other Enteroviruses [with J. R. Paul comments], 1962 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - "Oral Polio Vaccine" [Southbury Training School, Hartford, New Britain, Willimantic], 1962 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Poliomyelitis [Copenhagen], 1962 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - "Recent Advances in the Use of Polio Vaccines",[Hunt Memorial, Hartford Medical Society], 1962 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Current Status of Vaccination Against Poliomyelitis [Newark], [1963] (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Enteroviruses [Rio de Janeiro], 1963 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - "Live Virus Vaccination: Current Status Measles, Polio and Prospects for Rubella", 1963 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - New Measles Vaccine and The Current Oral Poliovirus Vaccine [Bridgeport Medical Association], 1963 (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - "Poliomyelitis Virus Vaccines" [Academy of Medicine of New Jersey], 1963 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - "Principles of Diagnostic Virology" in Viral and Ricketsial Infections of Man, fourth edition, 1963-1965 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - "Viral Meningitis in Cecil-Loeb Textbook of Medicine, 1963, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - "Enterovirus Infections of the Central Nervous System" [Association for Research in Nervous-Mental Disease], 1964 (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Natural Epidemic of Rubella in a Closed Population (Paris), 1964 (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - "Rubella" (San Francisco), 1964 (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - Enteroviruses (Madison), 1965 (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - "Rubella and the Rubella Syndrome-New Developments" [Connecticut State Medical Society, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - "Clinical Virology", 1966, 1967, 1970, 1972, undated (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - Description of Nobel Festivities, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - "Discussion of Paper by J. L. Melnick, 'Importance and Prospects for Control of Coxsackie and Echovirus Infections' " [Pan American Health Organization], 1966 (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - "Gamma Globulin, Uses and Abuses" [American Academy of Pediatrics. Seminar on Immunization, Providence], 1966 (Box 18, Folder 76)
  - "Immunization vs. Poliomyelitis" [Atlanta], 1966 (Box 18, Folder 77)
  - Pathogenesis of Poliomyelitis, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 78)
  - "Poliomyelitis and Other Enterovirus Infections of the CNS- Present and Future", 1966 (Box 18, Folder 79)
  - Rubella (Stockholm), 1966 (Box 18, Folder 80)
  - "Rubella" (Philadelphia), 1966 (Box 18, Folder 81)
  - Discussion of Session 6 of Conference on Experimental Medicine and Surgery in Primates [New York Academy of Sciences], 1967 (Box 18, Folder 82)
  - "Enteroviral Meningitis" (Albany), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 83)
  - Hepatitis (Kansas City), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 84)
  - Poliomyelitis (Lima, Peru), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 85)
  - Rubella (Peru), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 86)
  - "Rubella" [Conference of State and Territorial Epidemiologists, Atlanta], 1967 (Box 18, Folder 87)
  - "Viral Hepatitis. Eleventh Annual Symposium on Infectious Diseases" (Kansas City), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 88)
  - "Influenza and Other Respiratory Infections (San Francisco), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 89)
  - South African Report, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 90)
  - "Viral Exanthems (Johannesburg), 1969 (Box 18, Folder 91)
  - Rubella [St. Raphael's Hospital], 1969 (Box 18, Folder 92)
  - Rubella [World Health Organization Serum Bank], 1969 (Box 18, Folder 93)
  - Rubella [Women's Auxiliary, Yale -New Haven Hospital], 1969 (Box 18, Folder 94)
  - "Serological Responses Following Natural Infection" [Northeast Regional Conference on Rubella], 1969 (Box 18, Folder 95)
  - Adenovirus Pneumonia, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 96)
  - Immunization versus rubella [American Epidemiological Society, Seattle], 1970 (Box 18, Folder 97)
  - Rubella: The Challenge of Its Control [Annual Thomas Francis, Jr., Memorial Lecture], 1970 (Box 18, Folder 98)
  - Rubella (Ford Ord), 1970 (Box 18, Folder 99)
  - Rubella (Atlantic City), 1970 (Box 18, Folder 100)
  - Rubella (Copenhagen, Los Angeles), 1970 (Box 18, Folder 101)
  - Rubella vaccination (Edinburgh), 1970 (Box 18, Folder 102)
  - "Rubella Vaccine: Problems and Progress" [Phi Delta Epsilon Lecture], 1970 (Box 18, Folder 103)
  - "Rubella; Quantitative and Qualitative Differences in Immunity Following Vaccination and Natural Infection" with H. Lieber et. al., (Edinburgh), 1970 (Box 18, Folder 104)
  - Hepatitis (Los Angeles), 1971 (Box 18, Folder 105)
  - "Immunization Practices", 1971 (Box 18, Folder 106)
  - Meningococcal disease -vaccine (Newport, Irvine), 1971 (Box 19, Folder 107)
  - Zelda [book review], 1971 (Box 19, Folder 108)
  - Rubella, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 109)
  - Infectious Mononucleosis, [1972] (Box 19, Folder 110)
  - Rubella (Baltimore), 1972 (Box 19, Folder 111)
  - "Viral Infections in Pregnancy", 1972, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 112)
  - Poliomyelitis in Merck Manual, 1972-1980 (Box 19, Folder 113)
  - "CMV [cytomegalovirus] Infections", 1973 (Box 19, Folder 114)
  - "Neonatal Viral Infections", 1973 (Box 19, Folder 115)
  - Poliomyelitis: A Menace Gone Underground, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 116)
  - "Problems of the Rubella Vaccination Program" [Current Problems in Infectious Diseases and Their Treatments], 1973 (Box 19, Folder 117)
  - Rho antigen, [1973?] (Box 19, Folder 118)
  - John R. Paul, with Paul B. Beeson in Biographical Memoirs, National Academy of Sciences, 1973-1982 (Box 19, Folder 119)
  - "Problem of Infection in Pregnancy" [Bacchus Hospital], 1974 (Box 19, Folder 120)
  - Streptococcus Infections [Infectious Diseases Society of America], 1974 (Box 19, Folder 121)
  - Controlling Rubella: Problems and Perspectives [James Bruce Award], 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 122)
  - Viral Meningitis and Encephalitis, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 123)
  - Yale in China trip lectures, 1974-1975, undated (Box 19, Folder 124)
  - "Controlling Rubella: A Long Term Challenge" [Joseph E. Smadel Lecture], 1975 (Box 19, Folder 125)
  - "History of Rubella", 1975 (Box 19, Folder 126)
  - Infectious Diseases Society of America lecture, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 127)
  - "Neonatal Viral Infections" (Syracuse), 1975 (Box 19, Folder 128)
  - Streptococcus (Norwalk), 1975 (Box 19, Folder 129)
  - Immunization vs viral diseases (New Orleans), 1976 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - "Mumps", 1976 (Box 19, Folder 131)
  - "Remarks on the Occasion of the Dedication of the John R. Paul Seminar Room", 1976 (Box 19, Folder 132)
  - "Research and Development" [Summary, National Immunization Conference, National Institutes of Health], 1976 (Box 19, Folder 133)
  - Rubella [London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine], 1976 (Box 19, Folder 134)
  - Vaccine Induced Immunity to Rubella - Neutralizing and HAI Antibody Patterns Five Years After Vaccination, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 135)
  - "Changing Concepts in Infectious Diseases" [Fae Golde Kass Lecture], 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 136)
  - Measles, [1977] (Box 20, Folder 137)
  - "Measles Vaccination in the United States. Progress and Problems" (Copenhagen), 1977 (Box 20, Folder 138)
  - Graduation address [Yale School of Medicine], 1977 (Box 20, Folder 139)
  - Enteroviruses, 1977-1980, undated (Box 20, Folder 140)
  - Polioviruses in Textbook of Infectious Diseases, 1977-1981 (Box 20, Folder 141)
  - Problems in Measles and Rubella in Disease-a-Month, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 142)
  - Interview by Robert W. McCollum, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 143)
  - Response to a statement by J. Dudgeon [Symposium on Immunization, Brussels], 1978 (Box 20, Folder 144)
  - "Poliomyelitis" (San Francisco), 1978 (Box 20, Folder 145)
  - Rubella in the Vaccine Era - A Continuing Challenge (San Francisco), 1978 (Box 20, Folder 146)
  - Viral vaccines (Finland), 1978 (Box 20, Folder 147)
  - Vaccination against Rubella (San Francisco), (South Africa), 1978, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 148)
  - "Current Status of Measles and Polio", 1979 (Box 20, Folder 149)
  - "Immunization and the Control of Viral Infection" and "Fatal Infectious Mononucleosis and Possible Oncogeneity of the Epstein-Barr Virus" (South Africa), 1979 (Box 20, Folder 150)
  - "Measles and Rubella" [Connaught Scientific Seminar], 1979 (Box 20, Folder 151)
  - Measles, rubella, poliomyelitis immunization (Toronto), 1979 (Box 20, Folder 152)
  - "Rotavirus Infections" (Norwalk), 1979 (Box 20, Folder 153)
  - "Vaccines in the Control of Viral Infections" (Capetown), 1979 (Box 20, Folder 154)
  - "Long Term Surveillance of Rubella Vaccines" with Ann Schleuderberg", 1979-1984 (Box 20, Folder 155)
  - "Viral Infections" in Medical Complications During Pregnancy, 1979-1984 (Box 20, Folder 156)
  - "Fatal Infectious Mononucleosis and Polyclonal B Cell Lymphoma" [National Institutes of Health], 1980 (Box 20, Folder 157)
  - "Control of Poliomyelitis (Can the Disease Be Eliminated?)" (Stirling, Scotland), 1981 (Box 20, Folder 158)
  - Rubella Outbreak: Still a Threat to Hospital Personnel and Patients [Asepsis], 1981 (Box 20, Folder 159)
  - Poliomyelitis [Grover Francis Powers Lecture], 1982 (Box 20, Folder 160)
  - Poliomyelitis Control: A Continuing Paradox [Robert Ward Memorial Lecture], 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 161)
  - Presentation of the Squibb Award to George Miller, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 162)
  - Vaccines against Rubella, Measles, Poliomyelitis (Memphis), [1982?] (Box 20, Folder 163)
  - Congenital and Perinatal Viral Infections in Perinatal Epidemiology, 1982-1984 (Box 20, Folder 164)
  - "Introduction of Dr, Sabin as the Maxwell Finland Lecturer, Infectious Diseases Society of America", 1984 (Box 20, Folder 165)
  - "Poliomyelitis: The Scientific Conquest and Social Responses" [Dowling/Davis Lecture], 1984 (Box 20, Folder 166)
  - "The Present: Epidemiological Realities and Challenges" [Karl F. Meyer Lecture], 1985 (Box 20, Folder 167)
  - "Can Poliomyelitis Be Eradicated? Part 1: The Present Epidemiological Realities and Challenges" [Second Annual K. F. Meyer Lecture], 1985 (Box 20, Folder 168)
  - "Vaccination vs Rubella" (Prague), 1985 (Box 20, Folder 169)
  - Pathogenesis of Poliomyelitis [Symposium, Albert Sabin's eightieth birthday], 1986 (Box 20, Folder 170)
  - "Poliomyelitis: Pathogenesis and Control" Albert Sabin's birthday celebration], 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 171)
  - Remarks on the occasion of Arthur Ebbert's leaving the Deputy Dean position, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 172)
  - "The Polio Story" [Nathan Smith Club], 1988 (Box 21, Folder 173)
  - Three Landmark Articles About Poliomyelitis – Commentary, [reprint requests], 1992 (Box 21, Folder 174)
  - "Rubella" in Management of High Risk Pregnancy, third edition, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 175)
  - Obituary: James H. S. Gear, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 176)
  - "Isolation of Rubella Virus from Fetal Tissue and from Newborn Infants with Rubella Syndrome and Congenital Thrombocytopenic Purpura" [fragment, with J. E. Banatvala et. al.], undated (Box 21, Folder 177)
  - "Rubella Virus" (Johannesburg), undated (Box 21, Folder 178)
  - "Acute Respiratory Disease", undated (Box 21, Folder 179)
  - "Coxsackie Virus" ("C " Virus Infections"), undated (Box 21, Folder 180)
  - "Herpes Simplex", undated (Box 21, Folder 181)
  - "Infections Due to Mycoplasma Pneumoniae", undated (Box 21, Folder 182)
  - "Report on the Investigation of an Outbreak of Poliomyelitis in Beirut, Lebanon, July, 1952", undated (Box 21, Folder 183)
  - Rubella, undated (Box 21, Folder 184)
  - "Rubella Antibodies: Their Role in Protective Immunity" [abstract, with Ann Schluederberg], undated (Box 21, Folder 185)
  - Rubella (South Africa), undated (Box 21, Folder 186)
  - "Streptococcal Diseases and Rheumatic Fever" [Rheumatic Heart Disease lecture], undated (Box 21, Folder 187)
  - "Viremia after Ingestion of Oral Polio Vaccine\(Sabin)", undated (Box 21, Folder 188)
  - "Vaccinia", undated (Box 21, Folder 189)
  - Unidentified writing, undated (Box 21, Folder 190)
- Teaching, 1947-1983, Series III
  The series consists of a small number of teaching files from courses Horstmann taught at Yale in the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, the School of Medicine, and other university venues, as well as courses taught outside of Yale. The files are arranged by course title under a heading for each department or school in which she taught and include notes made in preparing for the course, outlines, course descriptions, instructors guides, charts, and bibliographies. In no case are all the lectures for an individual course available.
  - Epidemiology and Public Health
    - Principles of Epidemiology, 1947-1951, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Enterovirus infections, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - External [Environmental] Medicine, 1958-1961, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Rubella and the Rubella Syndrome" [Special lectures in medical microbiology], 1962-1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - International Epidemiology, 1969, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Epidemiology of Viral Infections, 1972, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Rubella and Other Neonatal and Congenital Infections, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "Rubella and Congenital Malformations", 1983 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Second year medical students
    - Poliomyelitis, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Rubella, 1965-1967 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Immunization, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Acute Viral Central Nervous System Infections, 1977-1979 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Grand Rounds
    - Rubella, 1962-1974, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Rubella Syndrome, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Aseptic Meningitis, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Rubella, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Other Yale University lectures
    - Poliomyelitis, Rubella [noon conferences], 1960, 1979, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Rubella [Helen Hadley Hall], 1966 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Poliomyelitis [Introduction to Epidemiology class,; Physicians Associates Program], 1980 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Outside of Yale University
    - Epidemiology Courses [University of Minnesota, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Continuing Medical Education [American Medical Society], 1977-1979 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Changing Concepts in Infectious Disease [Visiting professor, University of California School of Medicine], 1979 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Poliomyelitis Control, a Continuing Parado [Robert Ward Memorial Lectures], 1982 (Box 22, Folder 23)
- Research and Consultations, 1940-1990, Series IV
  The series contains extensive notes, data, and reports generated by Horstmann's work in the laboratory at Yale and during field studies around the world. The series contains notebooks, data sheets, and reports of projects. The materials are organized in three sections: Research notes on viruses, Field studies, and Administrative files.